# 你看 我們場裡面有這個葛根哦
Look! There are kudzu roots at our place.
# 不知道有沒有葛根蟲
There might also be kudzu root worms.
# 搞下來試一下
Let me take it down and have a look.
# 這麼大的包 應該有的
What a big pocket! There must be some inside.
# 你看 這裡葛根包
Look! Here's a kudzu root pocket.
# 不知道有沒有葛根
Let's see if there are kudzu root,
# 蟲
worms.
# 搞這個就直接把它對半
To do it, you simply need to split it into half,
# 破開
cut it open.
# 這樣玩刀把危險哦
But playing with a knife is really dangerous.
# 這個 最好就不要用刀
Well, better not use the knife.
# 哎喲 哎喲
Ayo, ayo!
# 哎喲
Ayo!
# 細皮嫩肉的
Smooth, soft and tender
# 你看 這個
Look! This is,
# 很嫩的哦
soft and tender.
# 這裡有一個
Here's one.
# 出來
Come out!
# 這個沒有啦
No more.
# 哇
Wa!
# 有得吃啦
We'll have a feast!
# 這個
Here are,
# 你看 那麼多的
look, so many!
# 我在想怎麼 怎麼做好吃
I'm thinking how, how I can make a delicious dish,
# 是油炸還是烤 (註︰他的「煎」就是「炸」，混「炸」就是「煎」，不寫明了，免得觀眾亂)
frying or grilling?
# 油炸算啦
Let's just fry them.
# 直接奶到油堆里
Just throw them into the oil,
# 油鍋裡面去
into the wok,
# 炸一下
and fry.
# 是不是沒地方住它們 都擠在這個包裡面
Don't they have other places to live? They're all squeezed in the pocket.
# 搞了一棵藤子
So here we have just a bit,
# 一棵葛根藤子 就搞了那麼一點點
from one, one kudzu root.
# 我們去先洗一下
Let's wash them.
# 洗乾淨一點
They need to be washed thoroughly,
# 它們會拉尿的
as they pee.
# 好啦 洗乾淨啦
Alright! They're clean now.
# 你看
Look!
# 等下放點鹽放點油 炒了它
Let me put some salt, put some oil, and fry them.
# 加點油
Put some oil.
# 油先把它倒進鍋裡面??? (註︰其實我聽到別的，我根據我聽到的來譯吧)
We need a bit more oil.
# 加點鹽
Put some salt.
# 現在把鍋燒熱一下
Now let's heat up the wok.
# 差不多啦
It's hot enough now.
# 我把這個倒下去啦
So I pour them into the wok.
# 差不多可以啦
It should be alright now.
# 哎呀
Aya!
# 好香啊
It smells great!
# 你看 剛剛還在活潑
Look! Just now they were still energetic,
# 剛剛還會動
they were still moving.
# 現在就
But now,
# 變成了在碗裡面裝著的那個菜
they're in a bowl and have become a...dish.
# 嗯
Um!
# 很香額
It smells really good!
# 你看
Look!
# 這種肉
The meat,
# 晶瑩剔透
is crystal clear.
# 吃起來 嘎嘣脆
Texture is, crispy.
# 可以喲 這種
It's not bad.
# 下次我要多搞一點
Let me get more next time.
# 這搞了太少啦
We have too few this time.
# 還不夠我一個人吃
That's not even enough for me alone.
# 你們就別看著了啊
You guys don't look at me.
# 這次的不給你們吃
That's nothing for you this time.
# 看著也沒有
There's no use looking at me.